Anjali Dharmik

+44 7467304854, anjali.dharmik@gmail.com
Address: 89, Springfield Road, London N11 1RL
LinkedIn GitHub theforage

Summary

6+ Years of Industrial experience in the fields of Data Science, Deep Learning, Machine Learning, Software engineering, Cloud, Automation, Big data, and analytics. A proactive and fast learning individual passionate about data and Artificial Intelligent, solving and building data science use cases with excellent practical and analytical skills.

Education

- Master of Science in Artificial Intelligence, Royal Holloway University of London, Egham, United Kingdom from 11 January 2021 to 11 January 2022.
- Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science, Rajiv Gandhi Technological University, India from August 2010 to August 2014 with the Distinction (7.51/10)

Employment History

- Data Scientist, Brady Technologies, London, United Kingdom (May 2022 to Present)
 - Brady working on our cloud-native SaaS solution for the energy and power trading markets.
 - Collaborate with the Product Director to define and evolve product vision ensuring product market leadership and growth
 - · Collaborate with the Engineering team on design and data requirements for Quantitative solutions
 - Define a strategy of scalability, especially in algorithm maintenance to ensure optimal balance of licence payments versus maintenance EPEX
 - Demand forecasting, Algorithmic trading, Renewables forecasting models with data streaming, data processing and data transformation
 - Design and deliver cloud-based Proof-of-Concept data services to store, process and analyse data.
 - Data mining, decision science and predictive analytics on short term risk management, risk reward strategies, power market trading activities, P&L, ideally within power trading markets using time series data – storage, processing, aggregation, nesting, clock change conversion using AutoML.
 - interact with existing and prospective customers, listening to customer requirements, developing Proof of Concepts and demos.

• Senior Machine Learning Engineer, Deep.Meta, London, United Kingdom (December 2021 to May 2022)

- Deep.Meta is an integrated Data Science and Metal Manufacturing Consulting business.
- Responsible for developing and delivering creative and bespoke technical solutions from conception through to production.
- Performing devising and researching technical solution using data collection, data verification, feature extraction, model building, testing, deployment and client interpretable presentation and delivery.
- My work covers a wide range of advanced statistical methods, including machine learning and optimization techniques (ensemble techniques and clustering).
- Leading, mentoring, and developing junior Machine Learning Engineer for their professional development

• Senior Data Scientist, Aress Software Pvt. Ltd, United Kingdom (November 2018 to December 2020)

- Aress Software is an integrated Data Science and Management Consulting business.
- Design and deploy innovative data science projects as part of a diverse and multi-functional team utilizing diverse spectrum from the data source.
- Identify and apply appropriate analytical techniques in building predictive and regulatory models.
- Build Python applications to extract, transform, and examine various types of data with robust pipelines. Deploy models using DevOps tools and production patterns.
- Data Scientist, BancTec & Data force UK (Rule14 LLC), United Kingdom (November 2017 to

November 2018)

- Offered a suite of solutions and services powered by **statistical analytics**, data science and insight on **large-scale datasets using Pyspark**.
- performed importing the data, understanding the data, cleaning the data, testing the data, training, and evaluating the model.
- worked in a multi-disciplined team to deliver projects to an agreed schedule according to the business roadmap.
- responsible to analyze and model structured and unstructured data using advanced statistical
 methods and performed full modelling projects to create linear and nonlinear models, including
 data ingestion, feature creation and selection, cross-validation, hyperparameter tuning and model
 assessment.
- collaborate with Product teams to drive new product ideas and increase the value of data science within the product and organization.

Software Engineer, BancTec & Data force UK (Exela Technologies), Pune, India (November 2016 to November 2017)

- Understood the requirement and provided training, accordingly, integrated all modules, deploy on a cloud server (AWS), and monitoring process.
- Deployed Solutions and monitor the performance of the model in production.
- Application Developer, Entercoms Solution Pvt. Ltd, Pune, India (April 2015 To November 2016)
 - Implemented **Data Science** and **Machine Learning** Algorithms using **Python** Programming to predict the **demand and supply** for **structured** and **unstructured datasets** to improve the business growth.
 - Applied mathematics, and statistical techniques to create scalable solutions for real-world problems.

Skill Set

Python, **R**, Data Analysis, Machine Learning, DevOps, Databases (**SQL**, NoSQL), Data Visualizations (PowerBI, matplotlib, seaborn, plotly, tableau), Statistics, Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, Jira, Git, **Spark**, pitching, Presentation, Strategic Planning, Unit testing, Word, Excel, Outlook, Powerpoint, Power BI, Tableau, AWS, AZURE, GCP, Haddop, Rshiny

Certificates

- Machine Learning, Stanford university
- Machine Learning in Production Specialization, Deeplearing.ai (Dev Ops)
- AWS Cloud Technical Essentials, AWS Elemental, an Amazon Web Services Company
- Deep Learning Specialization, Deeplearning.ai
- Natural Language Processing Specialization, Deeplearing.ai
- SQL Certificate, HackerRank
- Big Data Specialization, UC San Diego

Language

English, Hindi, Marathi

Achievements

- Awarded Royal Holloway Principal's Masters Scholarship and Computer Science scholarships.
- Employee of the month in April 2019 for splendid work.

Publications

COVID 19 Diagnosis Analysis using Transfer Learning -Deep LearningCOVID 19 Diagnosis Analysis using Transfer Learning -Deep Learning
 https://www.researchgate.net/publication/358229656 anjalidharmikC2022 IEEE COVID 19 Diagnosis Analysis using Transfer Learning -Deep Learning

Project

PowerDesk Edge

This is a data science **time-series analysis** for short-term energy trading market on real-time data from elexon to forecast the next demand and price for energy traders according to settlement date and period and excitement the risk. Decarbonisation and decentralisation are accelerating change and driving greater relevance to trading products in the short-term (prompt) market.

Brady PowerDesk provides the route to market for the short-term power trader. PowerDesk has all the tools you need to accelerate intraday and day-ahead power trading profits. Secure opportunities faster with intelligent visualisation of live P&L, net open positions, direct trading on EPEX and Nord Pool and TSO connectivity from a single dashboard.

• Market Price Direction Prediction Analysis

Market Price Direction Prediction Analysis, offering a state-of-the-art user experience for energy traders, hedge funds, asset owners and optimisers. The solution provides unrivalled connectivity to all the major European exchanges with real-time position and P&L management, enabling trading participants to operate with optimal efficiency in today's volatile gas, power and oil markets. This Analysis is mainly focus on Market Price Direction Prediction using EPEX and Elexon Data.

BancMate

This is a seamlessly integrated omni-channel banking and money management platform developed to help users gain more control over and do more with their money within a single application.